<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dervish Moose Blog</title>
    <description>I&#39;m not a moose and I don&#39;t dance, but I do know a thing or two about tech. I love to learn and I invite you to join me in my quest to learn more about tech.
</description>
    <link>http://locahost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://locahost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 22:45:52 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 22:45:52 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can we salad bar Black Lives Matter</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;Photo: Fibonacci Blue Creative Commons&lt;/span&gt;
When the organization I work for came out in support of parts of Black Lives Matter, my first thought was, “Wait you can do that? You can salad bar Black Lives Matter?” Can you take the parts you like and leave the things you don’t like in a movement? If you are a Christian, you already do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Black Lives Matter always seemed a long way away from me. I never took time to think about would I support BLM. As I started to put together the few things that I thought I knew about BLM, I realized that I did not know much about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is BLM the manifestation of, “Hey where is my jetpack?” from the 1960s civil rights movement? The 1960s civil rights movement left off with hope that someday the dream of Martin Luther King Jr. would be actualized. TV shows like Star Trek showed a utopian future where the dream came true. Is the Black Lives Matter movement of 2015 the group realization that the dream has not yet coming true and something needed to be done?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is the BLM movement, a pushback against the police system? On the surface the BLM protests seem to follow events of deaths of black civilians by police. There also seems to be a militant faction of the movement advising aggression and violence towards police officers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BLM seems to encompass all of the above and much more. To quote Greg Jao “Movements are messy”. My experience in movements seems to be, each person in the movement has their own idea what they movement is about. There is no authoritative structure in a movement to say here is the doctorial cannon that we follow. Very messy in deed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to look far to see a parallel between the messiness of BLM and the Christian Church or dare I say Christian Movement. We are masters of Salad Baring. Just look at the “taking and leaving” we do: Catholic vs Protestant, Calvin vs Arminian, Baptist Vs Presbyterian or even PCA Presbyterian Vs PCUSA Presbyterian. All of these things are labels for groups of beliefs or doctrines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you as a person or an organization support parts of a moments? Yes, you can. So I can now say that I support and align with parts of the Black Lives Matter Movement. Let’s start with the simple statement of anyone made in the likeness of God deserves safety, dignity and respect. Then as time goes on, let’s see what finer detail and specific items I can align with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 08:36:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://locahost:4000/faith/2016/01/10/blm-salad.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://locahost:4000/faith/2016/01/10/blm-salad.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Faith</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Serverless SlakBot, like PB &amp; J</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/lambda-slack.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
It’s like peanut butter and jelly. Good all by themselves, but way better together. Yum! Serverless (formerly JAWS) and Slack, BFF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have thought about wring a slack bot to do this or to do that, but I realized that I would need to spin up a server OR host the backend on an existing server. Since I have been preaching about technology debt a lot lately, I ate my own dog food and decided not to spin up my own server.  (… and also to not write a slackbot.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days ago serverless-slackbot was released. Serverless (formerly JAWS) leverages AWS Lambda and gives me a “spot” to store nodejs code that can respond to an API call.  There is no standing server to keep patched and updated. Thus greatly reducing the technology debt in deploying projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now, the only real problem left to me is, what was the really really cool thing I was going to build a slack bot for? I don’t remember. Oh, well I’ll be ready next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the Serverless Slack bot project page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;serverless-slackbot&quot;&gt;Serverless Slackbot&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A Serverless Module for the Serverless Framework featuring a SlackBot you can easily add skills to and package as a Slack Application, ready for distribution. All without servers!
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/serverless/serverless-slackbot&quot;&gt;Check out the project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 08:36:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://locahost:4000/web/2016/01/07/lambda-slack-bot.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://locahost:4000/web/2016/01/07/lambda-slack-bot.html</guid>
        
        <category>serverless</category>
        
        <category>slack</category>
        
        
        <category>Web</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rambo Architecture Vs Chaos Monkey</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
Ok you had me at Rambo Architecture…. but Rambo Architecture vs Chaos Monkey gotta read….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a fantastic article about Netflix using Amazon Web Services and maintaining uptime even if the cloud hosting is having issues. This article introduces “Rambo Architecture”- “Each system has to be able to succeed, no matter what, even all on its own.” And it also introduces “The Chaos Monkey” test scrips, that randomly turns off servers and data bases to make sure the Rambo Architecture keeps running. Stop I my inner server admin is 1/2 crying and 1/2 laughing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techblog.netflix.com/2010/12/5-lessons-weve-learned-using-aws.html&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 08:36:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://locahost:4000/web/2015/12/31/chaos-monkey.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://locahost:4000/web/2015/12/31/chaos-monkey.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Web</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Take on BUSH&#39;S® White Chicken Chili</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/chicken-chili.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;Photo &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jeffreyww&quot;&gt;jeffreyww&lt;/a&gt;  via flickr&lt;/span&gt;
It’s chili time again! With minor tweaks I won the crowd favorite in our office chili cook-off with this recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://allrecipes.com/recipe/bushs-white-chicken-chili/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Tweaks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gluten free flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More Beans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Season the chicken when cooking with red chili powder and smoked chipotle powder.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add lots of smoked chipotle powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding a good smoked Chipotle Powder is the hard part. I could not find a dark and smoky chipotle powder, so I made my own. The chipotle powder turned out almost black and is the source of the dark smoky yumminess of the Chicken Chili.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have tried McCormick’s Chipotle Powder is rather hot and not that smoky.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 08:36:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://locahost:4000/food/2015/12/15/chicken-chili.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://locahost:4000/food/2015/12/15/chicken-chili.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Food</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dutch Baby aka Big Pancake</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/dutch-baby.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Makes 2 large pancakes, 4-6 servings each (maybe 2 servings each… for big men)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 eggs
1 cup milk
1 cup flour
1 teaspoon sugar
3/4 teaspoon salt
1/4 cup (1/2 stick) unsalted butter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lemon wedges
Powdered sugar
Berries
Pure maple syrup&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat oven to 425° F.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whisk eggs, milk, flour, sugar and salt in a large bowl, or whiz in a blender. Let stand for 30 minutes at room temperature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Divide butter between two 9 or 10-inch cast iron skillets, glass baking dishes, or one larger rectangular roasting pan. Place in oven until butter melts. Remove pans, swirling butter to coat sides. Divide batter between pans. Bake on lowest rack until golden brown, set on center rack and allow to bake until sides rise high above the sides of the pans, 12-15 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slice pancake into wedges and serve with dusting of sugar, berries and a squirt of lemon juice, or just some good maple syrup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I don’t see much of any difference in the result of moving the skillets from the middle racks to the higher ones. I have done it both ways. It seems that you can just plan for 20-25 mins @ 425° F )&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 08:36:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://locahost:4000/food/2015/12/15/dutch-babby.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://locahost:4000/food/2015/12/15/dutch-babby.html</guid>
        
        <category>b-fast</category>
        
        
        <category>Food</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
